<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reflection on Karan Nadagoudar</title><link>https://karanrn.github.io/tags/reflection/</link><description>Recent content in reflection on Karan Nadagoudar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copright %copy; 2022, Karan Nadagoudar</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://karanrn.github.io/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lost In ...</title><link>https://karanrn.github.io/posts/2022/03/12/lost-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karanrn.github.io/posts/2022/03/12/lost-in/</guid><description>I am not sure if I can put my thoughts into the right words. Words are never neutral as we are bound by emotion in every action we take, with an anxious mind as mine simple statements/thoughts will take you spiraling down the bottomless pit. Long thoughts with a small pinch of worries are hard to summarize as they tend to lose their importance or hold on to the individual (read as me), it is soothing and tempting to dump your thoughts onto our journal or an article like this one.</description></item><item><title>Learning right from wrongs</title><link>https://karanrn.github.io/posts/2021/01/30/learning-right-from-wrongs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karanrn.github.io/posts/2021/01/30/learning-right-from-wrongs/</guid><description>Learn from the mistakes of others! You can’t live long enough to make them all yourselves. – Chanakya
Life will not give us much time to try all the options to find the best possible answer/solution for problems life throws at us. Everyone is not blessed with the best opportunities to learn from the first or first few experiences. There is no right or wrong answer to the problems in life it is the perspective of one’s situation.</description></item><item><title>What beach taught me?</title><link>https://karanrn.github.io/posts/2019/05/27/what-beach-taught-me/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://karanrn.github.io/posts/2019/05/27/what-beach-taught-me/</guid><description>Life is always a rough ride. There are weaker struggles as there are harder struggles. All of these struggles bring us the needed rewards. Life is filled with moments of giving and take. The more one gives the more stake one gets/takes. All the wins cannot be won without hardships. Once in a while life grounds us with greater force to realize our true self. It would be foolish to ignore them as mere coincidence, these high tidal hits gifts us the biggest learnings of life.</description></item></channel></rss>